Guide to the Office of Selective Service and Veterans Affairs, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of Selective Service and Veterans Affairs, Yale University, records
1940-1952
RU 815
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
(10 boxes)
The records consist of university and local selective service board memoranda; correspondence; book lists; and faculty, staff, and student files documenting the operations of the Yale Office for Selective Service and Veterans Affairs.
Yale University. Office for Selective Service and Veterans Affairs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-B (YRG 42-B), Records of Yale offices responsible for selective service and veterans' affairs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Selective Service and Veterans Affairs was the authorized representative of Yale University in all interactions with the Veterans Administration and the Selective Service. It assisted veterans enrolled at Yale in obtaining educational benefits. It also assisted students register for selective service.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of university and local selective service board memoranda; correspondence; book lists; and faculty, staff, and student files documenting the operations of the Yale Office for Selective Service and Veterans Affairs.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Draft registration; Veterans -- Education; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Office for Selective Service and Veterans Affairs
- Records, 1940-1947; Accession 19ND-A-174
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023.
  - Correspondence, Bulletins and Memoranda
    - Official Bulletins and Memoranda
      - Selective Service regulations, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Local Board memoranda, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Selective Service directives, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Report of the Director of Selective Service, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Report on Conscientious Objectors, 1942, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - National Roster Bulletins, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Office of Scientific Personnel, Bulletins and Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Deferment of Teaching Personnel, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Profs. Technical llanpower Si tuatlon, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Selective Service at Other Universities, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous Selective Service Information, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - University Bulletins, Memoranda, etc.
      - Committee on Selective Service, Yale memos and minutes, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Student Registration and Deferment, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - University Buildings, Equipment and Manpower Survey, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Memorandum to National Selective Service, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Selective Service - Correspondence
      - National Headquarters Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - State Headquarters, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - State Headquarters other than Connecticut, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1941-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Chemistry, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Engineering, Fchool of, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Instructors Ages 18-25, 26-29, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Navy V-12 Instructors Correspondence, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Foreign Area Studies, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Medical School, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Physics, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Psychology, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Miscellaneous Departments and Schools, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Service Bureaus, 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Selective Service Registrations
      - Registration Data General, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Registrations, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Registrations, 1942-1942 (Box 3, Folder 33 - 34)
      - Replacement Schedule University Forms, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Student Deferment, 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Official forms (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Data re: All Departments
      - Miscellaneous: Statistics, 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Faculty Questionnaires, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Faculty and Service Staff, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Replacement Schedule
      - Search for Replacements, 1944 January (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Operating Personnel, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Scientific and Technical Departments, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Principal Liberal Arts War Teaching Depts, 1943-44 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Replacement Schedule, 1944 March - September (Box 4, Folder 45 - 48)
    - Non-Essential Personnel
      - General Liberal Arts Teaching Departments, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Faculty, Arts and Science General Administrative Offices, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - B.M.I. Personnel Records, 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - B.M.I. Bills, Budgets, etc.
      - Budgets- etc., 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Bills, 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Bills, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Committee on Student Preparation for War Service - Budgets, Bills and Orders, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1941-1947 (Box 5, Folder 56 - 57)
  - II. Faculty Files
    - A-C (Box 6, Folder 1 - 5)
    - D-G (Box 7, Folder 6 - 11)
    - H-L (Box 8, Folder 12 - 17)
    - L-O (Box 9, Folder 18 - 24)
    - P-S (Box 10, Folder 25 - 28)
    - S-W (Box 11, Folder 29 - 34)
    - W-Z (Box 12, Folder 35 - 37)
    - Service Staff and Technicians A-K (Box 12, Folder 38 - 48)
    - Service Staff and Technicians M-Z (Box 13, Folder 49 - 59)
  - III. Student Files
    - A-B (Box 14, Folder 1 - 5)
    - B-D (Box 15, Folder 6 - 11)
    - D-G (Box 16, Folder 12 - 16)
    - G-H (Box 17, Folder 17 - 24)
    - H-L (Box 18, Folder 25 - 32)
    - L-M (Box 19, Folder 33 - 39)
    - N-R (Box 20, Folder 40 - 47)
    - R-S (Box 21, Folder 48 - 52)
    - S-T (Box 22, Folder 53 - 58)
    - T-Z (Box 23, Folder 59 - 68)
    - Yale Student Quota
      - Data Regarding Students Considered for Quota (Box 24, Folder 69)
      - National Roster Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 70)
      - Student Quota Questionnaire (Box 24, Folder 71)
    - Alien Student (Box 24, Folder 72)
    - Divinity School (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - Pre-medical Students (Box 24, Folder 74)
    - Pre-Theological Students (Box 24)
    - Student Lists
      - Undergraduate Student Lists (Box 24, Folder 75)
      - Professional and Graduate Student Lists (Box 24, Folder 76)
      - Staff File (Box 24, Folder 77)
- Book lists, circa 1944-1952; Accession 19ND-A-175
  - Book lists, circa 1944-1952 (Box 1–6)